Jun Kang

718-986-0220 | jkang34@gmail.com

Github | LinkedIn | junekang.dev

Versatile Full Stack Software Engineer experienced in JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, React, HTML5, CSS, educated at the Flatiron School. Background in customer services and physical therapy really taught me the patience of solving problems and allowed me to think outside of the box. One of the reasons that drove me to become a Software Engineer was the joy of providing solutions to help and change the lives of people on a global scale. Being in this field allows me to grow to improve myself, reminding me that learning never stops.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Grooveit | Demo

Users are able to learn to dance by watching videos and uploading videos of their progress as well.

- Used Postgres to store the database.
- Designed Auth Token to enable the user to log in and sign up.
- Utilized Netlify to host the frontend and Heroku to host the backend of the web application.
- Created React components that users can comment and rate on the tutorial videos.
- Applied a simple algorithm, which the ratings shown in each of the videos are the average ratings of all the users who rated the video.

Day Maker | Demo

Web application for creating randomized activities to spend the day.

- Operated the controllers from the backend of the application to create randomized events for a day.
- Generated a function that prevents the user from getting the same event/restaurant on the same day.
- Designed the web application using Semantic UI and custom CSS.
- Before the users are logged in or signed up to the application, they are able to see all the restaurants and attractions
 that the application has to offer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby - Rails - React - Javascript - HTML - CSS - SQL - Heroku - Netlify - Wordpress

EXPERIENCE

Catchafire NY, NY

Volunteer

10/2021 - present

- Aiding foundations and organizations with technical bugs in their websites such as: stripe payment process, wordpress plugins, and components of the website.
- Helping companies with styling of their websites, providing feedback, and changes that can be made.

Flatiron School (Software Engineering program)

NY, NY

Software Engineering Student

11/2020 - 03/2021

- Learned the basics of Ruby and Javascript, how functions work, and learned the idea behind how frameworks are applied to web applications.
- Created projects from CLI to UI applications using Rails, Postgres, and React.
- Solved coding challenges by writing algorithms, creating functions, and components to React.
- Designed projects using CSS and Semantic UI.
- Learned the process of debugging programs and using API in web applications.

Oshman & Barteck Physical Therapy

Ny, NY

Physical Therapist Aide

08/2019 - 03/2020

- Assisted in the treatment of patients by securing patients onto therapy equipment, monitoring patient progress and mobility.
- Instructed and motivated patients during exercise sessions, under direction of a physical therapist.
- Observed treatment sessions to compile data on patient progress and responses.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

11/ 2020 - 03/2021

NY. NY

University at Buffalo BA in Psychology Buffalo, NY 09/2010 - 09/2015